Wrege, Charles D. Collection of History of Management Documents 6014
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Charles D. Wrege Collection of History of Management Documents
1896-2011
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Wrege, Charles D.
6014
4.11 cubic feet
4.1 linear ft.
Papers.
Original documents from Hawthorne Studies and photos from the Western Electric Works.
5758016
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, July 21, 2014
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, August 13, 2015
Biographical / Historical
Charles "Chuck" Wrege finished his undergraduate degree in Upsala College, obtained his Masters degree at the New School fo Social Research and another Masters of Business Administration and his Ph.D. at NYU. He taught industrial management at Rutgers University for 30 years. He became a renowned historian, researcher and writer. He is regarded as a "National Treasure" by many in his field because of his expertise and the seminal research he has done in the area of management history.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Wrege, Charles D.
5758016
- Original Documents. Hawthorne Studies. Includes photos (moved to collection 6014 P) from the Western Electric Works. Hawthorne in 1979 Chicago. When the works were torn down almost all of them disappeared. R. Greenwood and CD Wrege had lots of copie (Box 1)
  - F.W. Taylor House at 735 Delaware Ave South Bethlehem PA 1899 (from 1912 Sanborn Map) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence with Michael Pallak, Ed. Amer Psychologist on Bramel and Friend articles 1981-1982 HAWTHORNE (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - AMA Account of Hawthorne Studies (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Scope and Contents
    no dates
  - ORIGINAL- Piece Rates Conversion Figures for Relay Test Room from Richard Frazier (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - ORIGINAL- Actual Output Chart in Test Room - Weeks 29-40 by CD Wrege 1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - ORIGINAL - Photo of Homer Hibarger-Creator of Relay Assembly Test Room at Hawthorne, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - ORIGINAL - Copy of Memorandum by W.J. Dickerson on Hawthorne Illumination Test on Snow - June 13, 1956 (File under Snow) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    from Homer Hibarger
  - ORIGINAL - Report on "Special Illumination Test by H. Hibarger 2/14/27 (5 pages), 1927 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    folder 1. Report on "Special Illumination Test by H. Hibarger 2/14/27 folder 2. ORIGINAL - Report on "Special Illumination Test by H. Hibarger 2/14/27 (5 pages)
  - Homer Hibarger ORIGINAL Letter on His Work at Hawthorne July 1, 1959 and July 6, 1956, 1956-1959 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Book Log" of Management and the Worker (2 pages) Photographic Copy of Original - Original Missing as of June 19, 1979 *ONLY KNOWN COPY (Box 1, Folder 10)
    ONLY KNOWN COPY *Copy obtained through series L Code 1959. Robert Levett of Harvard, on June 19, 1979m could not find original
  - Robert Lovett Letter of 6/19/79 on Being Unable to Locate "Book Log" on Missing Book Log (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Letter on "Book Log" Missing June 19,1979
  - Original Only Copy of Letter from George F. Lombard on Mayo Material at Harvard Nov 7, 1957 (Hawthorne Studies- MAYO) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Original Memo from Letter Mayo to Clarence Stall (1928) on Types of Studies do in Riley Test Room at Hawthorne *, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    ORIGINAL * From Clarence Stall (ex president of Western Electric) Sept 1957 CDW
  - Correspondence from Lombard on Mayo 1. 10/15/57 ORIGINAL, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Elton Mayo's Handwritten Notes, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    -on yellow memo -Oct 14, 1927-on early report on Hawthorne -2 white notes (misc. notes) and Buff notes on Continental Mills, ???
  - Copy of Original Elton Mayo Letter to George A. Pennock (Hawthorne) 5/9/27 *, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Original Carbon Copy * Received from Richard Frazier of MIT (who worked at Hawthorne) in 1984 (copy of letter apparently given to Frazier to prepare paper for Pennock) CDW
  - Original - Confidential Report on Lyndale Urwick - F. Mayo (no date, 4 pages) (Box 1, Folder 17)
    no date
  - Misc. Telephone Booklet on Recorder Hawthorne Material * (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Original Booklet- * This unit modified and used to record output in relay test room
  - Original Photo-Photograph of Converted Markroom-Klein Schmidt Recorder in Test Room, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    (negatives at Western Electric NOW MISSING -CDW 8/10/96)
  - Original Sheet from John Oliva Showing Method of Calculating Earnings in Test Room 1981 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Original Memorandum by William J. Dickson on Illumination Experiments at Hawthorne, June 18, 1956 *, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    ORIGINAL *from Homer Hibarger, 1957 also copy of Dickson letter of June 20, 1956 on above memorandum CDW
  - Photograph of Charles E. Snow Original from Western Electric Personnel Files, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - C.E. Snow :Research on Industrial Illumination" Tech Eng. News Nov. 1927 [Negative Photostats] (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Authors report differs slightly from his published article
  - Copy of Original article by Snow, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Found by CD Wrege in NY Publication, 1957 * (*This is the original copy made at NY Public Library in 1957 by CD Wrege)
  - Original 1924 Memorandum on Hawthorne Test (Box 1, Folder 25)
    August 1924
  - Educational Opportunities at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - John A. Scott Letter of August 15, 1957 to C.D. Wrege on Hawthorne studies (Illumination Test) ORIGINAL (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Original Stoll Letter on Hawthorne, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Original letter of Mr. Clarence Stoll on Hawthorne Illumination Tests September 3, 1957
  - 3 Pages from Charles E. Snow's Original Log Notes, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    1) 2-21-25, 2) 2-11-25, 3) 2-24-25
  - Report on Illumination and Typesetting (from C.E. Snow 1950) Original CD Wrege (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Original - John Parsons (MIT) letter on Dennison Illumination Tests Nov. 9, 1925 - (from C.E. Snow) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Survey of Air Conditions 1924-1925 Tests (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Copy of Snow original
  - C.E. Snow "Report on Second Year's Tests at the Hawthorne Works of the Western Electric Company", 1926 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Original copy of report, 14 pages & 5 page appendix. Note: pages are also numbered (M-293 -- M-318) [referring to microfilm copy of report]. 1926 report
  - Original Photo of Light Test Room at Hawthorne for 1926-1927 Tests - from Snow Report 1926-1927 Test (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Charles E. Snow Hawthorne Record Output in 1926-1927 Tests Original (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Original - 3 Sheets on Output in 1926-1927 Tests- Typed (Compared to Hawthorne Record) (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Original Snow Letters of April 7, 1961 & April 24, 1961 on Hawthorne Illumination Tests (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Original - Carbon Copy on MIT Watermark Stationary of Feb 23, 1927 Letter P.C. Jackson to G.A. Pennock * (Box 1, Folder 38)
    *from C.E. Snow folder 1926-1927 Tests CD Wrege
  - Snow 1927 on "Sickness Rate" Xerox (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Original - Various Original Pages from Snow on 1926-1927 Test at Hawthorne - As Follows * (Box 1, Folder 40)
    * Pages numbered 1 to 6 on upper right hand corner. Table I (no date) (page 1); Table II (no date) for test group (p. 2) (for control group (p. 3); Table III Avg of test output & control group (2 pages numbered 4 & 5); Table IV Weekly average of temperature and humidity (page 6)
  - Original Pages from Snow on 1926-1927 Tests * (Box 1, Folder 41)
    * in red "Table I" - dated May 2, 1927- Summary of Test & Control Group Also: Take I - with M361 on top right May 2, 1927 [means it is in microfilm copy of CD Wrege of output records]; Table III (2 pages) marked M363 & 364 on top right; Separate pages dated: Dec. 30, 1926; Feb 15, 1927; March 1, 1927; March 11, 1927
  - Original Pages from Snow's 1926-1927 Report on Illumination Tests at Hawthorne (Oct. 28, 1926; Dec 10, 1926; Jan 19, 1927; Jan 21, 1927) (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Original Sheet from Charles E. Snow, March 1, 1927, on original results of 1926-27 Tests (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Original 1926 Illumination Test Chart by C.E. Snow 1926-chart 111 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Drawing H1 & H2 Original of "A" Type Relays 1924-1925 Tests by C.E. Snow (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - C.E. Snow Data Dept. 6325 Coil Winding #46 Induction Coils 1924-1925 Tests C-1 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - C.E. Snow Data Dept. 6325 Coil Winding Receiving Coils 1924-1925 Tests C-2 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - C.E. Snow Coil Winding Dept. [Dept. 6325] Induction Coils (showing duration of production) 1924-1925 Tests C-3 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - C.E. Snow Dept. 6325 Coil Winding #46 Induction Coils - (Comparison Curve of Operators NOT in Lighted Area) 1924-1925 Tests C-4 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - C.E. Snow- Dept. 6325 Building 47-5 "Hourly Illumination Averages" (by lighting period) 1924-1925 Tests [Coil Winding] C-5 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - C.E. Snow Chart Dept. 6329 Building 39-5 "Hourly Illumination Averages" (by lighting periods) 1924-1925 Tests [Relay Assembly] C-6 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - C.E. Snow Chart Dept. 6643-5, Building 37-4 "Hourly Illumination Averages" (by lighting periods) 1924-1925 Tests [Inspection Dept.] C-8 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - C.E. Snow Data Dept. 6643-5 Inspection #92Jack Sheh, P.P. 101577 (visual inspection) C-10 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - C.E.S. Drawing No. H-2 [Dec. 1924-Aprril 1925] (on Dept. 6643-5 "Inspection") [Reproduced for WETP - 4 pages] 12, 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - C.E. Snow Chart H-3 "Induction Coil Winding Group" 1924-1925 Test Report (page 41a) [in envelope] 13 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Drawing H-4 of - 14, 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - C.E. Snow Drawing H-4 [Dec. 1924-April 1925] (on Dept. 6325-Coil Winding "Control Group") [reproduced for WETP-2 pages] - 15, 1924- 1925 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Drawing H-6 - 16, 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - C.E. Snow Chart H-7 "Frequency Distribution of Output Per Hour, Induction Coil Winding" [Dec 8 to March 25] [1924-1925 Test] - 17 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - C.E. Snow Chart H-8 "Frequency Distribution of Output Per Hour 144 Receiver Coil Winding Dec. 8 - April 11" [1924-1925 Test] - 18 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - C.E. Snow Chart H-9 -20, 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Drawing H-10 -21, 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - H-11 -22, 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - H-12 -23, 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - H-13 - 24, 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Drawing H-14 -25 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - H-15 -26 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - C.E. Snow Drawing H-16 -27 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Drawing H-17 - 28 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Drawing H-18 -29 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - C.E. Snow Chart of Illumination Test 1924-25, 1926 Charts H-51 -30, 1924-1926 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - H-52 -31 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - H-55 -34 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - H-56 -35, 1924-1926 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - H-57 -36, 1924-1926 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Drawing H-6 - 37, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Drawing H-62 -38, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - H-53 - 32, 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - C.E. Snow Chart H-64 "Induction Coil Winding, Test Group" [Avg. Prod. Rate at Different Hours of Day] 1924-1925 Compared -40 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - H-63 -39, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - C.E. Snow Drawing H-65 "Induction Coil Winding Control Group" 1924-1925 and 1926 Test - 41, 1924-1926 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Drawing H-66 - 42, 1924-1926 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - H-67 -43 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - C.E. Snow Chart H-68 "Weekly Average Production Induction Coil Winding" ;During May-Dec, 1925 and Jan.-March, 1926] -44, 1925- 1926 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - C.E. Snow Chart on Direction of Production-Relay Assembly Department [Dept. 63 29]-E Type Relays (1924-1925 Tests) #49 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - C. E. Snow [Dept. 6643-5] Inspection Department Jack Springs "Direction of Production" 1924-1925 Tests #50 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - C.E. Snow [Dept. 6643-5] Chart on Inspection Department #92 Jack Shells-Showing Direction of Production-1924-1925 Tests #51 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - From C. E. Snow Files [Cobb Studies] Blueprint on Speed of Vision Test for C.I.L. of N.R.C. (June 18, 1925) to (data from p. 96 table III Jl. Of Exper Psycho. April 1925) #52, 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - From C.E. Snow Files Blueprint Showing Comparisons of Hawthorne, Timken, Detroit Piston Ring and Ives Results [no date] #53 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - C.E. Snow Chart Comparing #54, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 90)
    1. Detroit Piston Ring Tests 2. Ives Post Office Tests 3. Harrison Timke Roller Bearing [Drawing Made 1924] CDW
  - Original Jack Spring Inspection Chart - 1924-1925 Tests by C.E. Snow (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Negative Photostat of: Hawthorne Microphone November 21, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 92)
    "Hawthorne Invited to Co-operate in Scientific Tests"
  - C. Wrege and R. Greenwood - Notes on Photos in Hawthorne Works Files 11/26/79, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - 35 mm Slides of Hawthorne Studies - Individuals - From Don Greenwood Originals, 1921-1926 (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Color Photographs of Hawthorne Works of Western Electric Co. Chicago, IL -1979 Original (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Original Photo of #46 Induction Coil at Hawthorne - 2/12/25, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Original Photos of Hawthorne Illumination Test, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Copy of Letter to Bob Lovett-June 21, 1979-on Missing Mgt. & Worker "Book Log" (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Early Photo of Willimatic Co. Linen Co. Electric Light Installation 2/14/791979 (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Foote Brothers Stromberg Motor Devices Companies in Chicago Durgin Photos 1918 (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - William Durgin Photo of Pyott Foundry Co. Chicago 1918-Original & "Productive Lighting" (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Original Photo of Relay Assembly Test Room at Hawthorne (From Snow 1924-25 Report), 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - Night Photographs of Hawthorne Relay Assembly Dept.- 4-10-25 and 3-6-25 Photos 135676 and 135679, 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - Photograph of Relay Assembly Dept. from Snow 1924-1925 Report Printed in "Labor Histories" Cornell 1982 (Box 1, Folder 104)
  - Assembly E Type Relay. Relay Assembly Dept. 1925-Photo #131671 (Box 1, Folder 105)
  - Enlargement of Order Section of Relay Assembly Dept. 1925 (portion 135676) (Box 1, Folder 106)
  - Original Photograph of E-Type Relay 1925-Photo #131677 from Snow 1924-1925 Report (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - Photograph of Coil Winding Dept. 1925 from Snow 1924-1925 Report #135682 (Box 1, Folder 108)
    3-6-25
  - Inspection Dept. at Hawthorne 3-6-25 Photo #135675 - Night View - from Snow 1924-1925 Report (Box 1, Folder 109)
  - Sorting Jack Springs in Inspection Dept. Hawthorne 1925 (Box 1, Folder 110)
  - Coil Winding Dept. S.E. Corner in 1925 & 1927 Originals (Box 1, Folder 111)
  - 1926-1927 Light Test Room at Hawthorne 1926 Photo #142902 (Benday Screen for Publishing) (Box 1, Folder 112)
  - Permalloy Loading Coil (Photo 133524) 2-21-25, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 113)
  - Marty Labno's 1981 Photo of Building 47-5 (July 27, 1981) Site of Relay Test Room 8 1926-27 Illum. Tests Plus Sketch (Box 1, Folder 114)
  - Original Photo of Coil Winding Test Room at Hawthorne in the 1926-1927 Tests (Box 1, Folder 115)
  - Coil Box Photo in Relay Test Room (Box 1, Folder 116)
  - 35mm Slides of Hawthorne and Joseph & Feiss Co (Box 1, Folder 117)
  - Original-Advertisement of Industrial Lighting Committee of the National Electric Light Assoc (Box 1, Folder 118)
    Designed to counter bad results of 1924-1925 Illumination test at Hawthorne CDW
  - Photographs of 1926 Advertisements on Industrial Lighting - Copies of Originals (Box 1, Folder 119)
  - Drawing D-1 of Dennison Illumination Tests N.R.C. 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 120)
  - Original Invitation to Demonstration on Factory Lighting Boston 1924 (Box 1, Folder 121)
  - Hanson Report on Industrial Illumination (1920) (Box 1, Folder 122)
  - Clair Turner -1933 Article on Hawthorne-Original (Box 1, Folder 123)
  - 1959 & 1964 Letter with Dr. Clair Turner on Hawthorne (Box 1, Folder 124)
  - "Original AHO" [Avg. Housing Output] From MIT [Turner] 9-31 Periods 1-10 (Box 1, Folder 125)
    Copy of original at Harvard discovered by C.D. Wrege 8/24/79 Originals may be MISSING Snow -due to Harvard's poor filing system CD Wrege
  - Morris S. Viteles 1958 on Hawthorne Studies Original from Viteles (Box 1, Folder 126)
  - Morris S. Viteles (1959) on Hawthorne Studies Original Copy of Speech (Box 1, Folder 127)
  - T, Whitehead Letter to CD Wrege (Feb. 21, 1964) on Hawthorne (Box 1, Folder 128)
    Original Missing
- Original Documents including letters from Barth to Keppele Hall, Thompson, and others.. (Box 2)
  - The Lehigh Ledger in Lehigh Alumni Bulletin May, 1965, p. 17-on Barth's Slide Rule and Bibliography (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Carl Barth Chart on Benefits of Scientific Management (1924) prepared by J. Christian Barth March 31, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - J.C. Barth Blueprint of F.W. Taylor's Functional Organization Chart at Bethlehem Steel, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Barth Data (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Letter from J. Christian Barth 1958-1968 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - J. Christian Barth Letter 1/10/59, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Letter to Christian Barth (one page) - 4/12/59, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Barth & Scientific Management Letter to J.C. Barth 1/14/59, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Postcard from J.C. Barth 2/15/59, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1959 Letters with J. Christian Barth on Scientific Management Originals (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1960 Letters to J.C. Barth Originals (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - J. C. Barth Data on Scientific Management, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    1. dated 4/25/59 2. 1960
  - G.A. Gulowsen Obituary 1923, ACME Transactions, Vol. 45, p. 903 Taylor (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Various Barth Charts (Transparencies), 1915 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - J. C. Barth Letter to R. Lovett (of Harvard) June 23, 1962 also Lovett interview of Barth Oct. 6, 1959, 1959-1962 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Barth Collection at Harvard - Christian Barth Letter of Jan 23, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Letter from J. Christian Barth July 17, 1964 (on Henry Knoll at Bethlehem) (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Eric Breitbart's "Clockwork" 1982 (on F.W. Taylor) Original Postcards on Breitbart Film (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - William B. Cornell, NYU. Booklet to Mrs. Wallace Clark on "Finding Brains for Business" (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Ernest Dale Letter 1964 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Development Day and Zimmerman Original Booklet 1918 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    friend of F.W. Taylor used Taylor Method
  - Progress - vol 1, no. 3 April 24, 1919-Published by Day & Zimmerman Co. (Charles Day) (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - R. Feiss Forms for Clothcraft (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Original Clothcraft Publications & Feiss Notes Plus May Hennan 1919 Paper (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Herman Hutkin Data (related to Feiss) 1977-78, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Original Feiss Notes on the Reorganization of Clothcraft Shops (No Date) (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Clothcraft Shop Photo 1924 from FDR Library 1976 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Publications of R.A. Feiss (list), 1964 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    from Mrs. Feiss
  - Feiss on Women at Work 1914 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - R.A. Feiss "High Grade Clothing" Speech -1919 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    In: The Clothing Designer & Manufacturers pp. 170- 172
  - Feiss in Factory Nov-Dec 1914-March 1915, 1914-1915 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - "Lizzie Likes Her Job" Prof. John R. Commons Booklet (Original), 1920 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    from the Independent Magazine, Nov. 6, 1920 (on Feiss Plant)
  - From Feiss Original-Harvard Alumni Bulletin Feb 1, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Original Feiss Articles, 1914-1943 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Original of Feiss Report July 18, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Original Copy of Richard A. Feiss' Paper on "Stabilization of Employment" March 4, 1928 (2 pages) (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Human Relations in a Scientific Organization of Industry (from Richard A. Feiss files-original 5 sheets) 9/4/1929 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    6 pages
  - "A Plan for the Regulation of Business and the Assurance of Employment" R.A. Feiss Dec. 1931 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Feiss- Oct. 1924 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Richard A. Feiss-Letter to President Truman et al 1945 (Wendell Willkie etc.), 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Feiss Letters (original), 1924-1927 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Miscellaneous Letters of Richard Feiss-from Mrs. Feiss 1979, 1925-1953 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Richard Feiss & Needle Trades 1919 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Henry H. Farquhar, Hawthorne Business School 5/12/1922-On Taylor Endowment & Carl Barth and Feiss reply 5/16/22 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Feiss Letter of Jan. 8, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Feiss Letters to Harvard 1922-1923 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Richard A. Feiss Letter to Kepple Hall Feb. 10, 1926 & Feb 19, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Percy Brown to R.A. Feiss April 25, 1928 Copy of Original (in 20th Century Fund Files in NYC) (See International Mgmt. Institute Files-CDW) (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Obituaries of People Associated with R.A. Feiss, 1923-1975 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Letter from Mary Hensen Feiss to Mr. Petrano, 11/12/64 and Feiss Expense Sheet for July 8, 1925 (Joseph C. Feiss Co), 1964 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Wrege & Petracca (from Mrs. Feiss - 1978), 1927-1964 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Letter to Mrs. Richard A. Feiss from Mary Gilson-on C,D, Wrege received from Mrs. Feiss - June 2, 1979), 1954-1959 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Letters to Mrs. R.A. Feiss 1977 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Richard A. Feiss Files, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Letter to P.S. Florence (Originals this original chart of 1919 on output)* October 1965 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    *Data used for Methods in Relay Assembly Test Room at Hawthorne
  - P. Sargent Florence Methods for Field Study of Industrial Fatigue 1918 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Industrial Fatigue - Committee on Labor Wash, DC-1918 Original Booklet (Box 2, Folder 57)
    From Phillip Florence
  - Letters from Lillian Gilbreth to C.D. Wrege March 14, 1958 Also Data on Gilbreth's Book Fatigue Study 1916, 1916-1958 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Letters from Ernestine Gilbreth Carey to C.D. Wrege, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Correspondence with Mary. B. Gilson July 8, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - 1957 Letters to Mary B. Gilson on Hawthorne (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - 1957-Postcards from Mary B. Gilson on Taylor, Cooke & Feiss (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Mary Gilson (IR Counselors NYC) Impressions of British General Strikes Summer, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - John Hader Pamphlet & Chart * 1957 (and earlier) (Box 2, Folder 64)
    *chart has been used in mgmt textbooks by authors as their own CDW
  - Pages from Keppele Hall's Study of the Lockwood Greene and Co. 1926 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Keppele Hall "The Planning Dept." 1923 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Keppele Hall Letters Original, 1910-1926 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    Original Keppele Hall Papers 1910, 1926
  - Keppele Hall - "Standardization of Paper" Paper Jan. 19, 1916 Original Articles (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Keppele Hall, Blueprint of Central Board at Joseph & Feiss Co. 2/26/26, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Keppele Hall - Resume with Notes by his Wife Fanny Hall, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Keppele Hall Resume - December 15, 1925 Original (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Pages 14 & 19 of Report on Taylor System of Stores - Keppele Hall Records 1925 Original (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Keppele Hall Correspondence, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Keppele Hall Booklet 5/2/1924 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Keppele Hall Program for R.A. Feiss of Absence & Home Visits 10/26/1919 Original (Box 2, Folder 75)
    Original Keppele Hall 1919 Chart